Anne Henrietta Martin Papers BANC MSS P-G 282
The Bancroft Library
Anne Henrietta Martin Papers
1834-1951
1900-1951
The Bancroft Library
Martin, Anne, 1875-1951
BANC MSS P-G 282
Linear feet: 25 Boxes: 19; Cartons: 10; Volumes: 12
Papers pertaining to Martin's activities for woman suffrage, feminism, social hygiene, and pacificism. Also included are materials relating to her U.S. Senate campaigns in Nevada in 1918 and 1920. Correspondents include: Dean Acheson, Jane Addams, Gertrude Atherton, Mary Austin, Mary Ritter Beard, Carrie Chapman Catt, Katherine Fisher, Henry Ford, Charlotte Perkins Gilman, Herbert Hoover, Cordell Hull, Belle La Follette, Henry Cabot Lodge, Margaret Long, H.L. Mencken, Francis G. Newlands, Alice Paul, Key Pittman, Jenette Rankin, Theodore Roosevelt, Upton Sinclair, Margaret Chase Smith, Lincoln Steffens, Dorothy Thompson, Mabel Vernon, Charles Erskine, Scott Wood, Margaret Wood, and Maud Younger. The correspondence is supplemented by a large bulk of manuscripts and notes, pamphlets, magazine and newspaper clippings, campaign miscellany, suffrage material, personalia, and scrapbooks.
Alternate Forms Available
Correspondence with Lincoln Steffens: also available on a partial reel of microfilm (negative [Rich. 119:5] and positive [X-X 1 FILM]).
Correspondence with Upton Sinclair: also available on a partial reel of microfilm (negative [Rich. 401:4] and positive [X-X 5 FILM]).
Related Collections
Mabel Vernon Papers, 1914-1920 (BANC MSS P-G 283)
Nevada Woman Suffrage Miscellany, 1914-1918 (BANC MSS P-G 284)
Material Cataloged Separately
Photographs transferred to The Bancroft Pictorial Collections (BANC PIC 1951.006--PIC).
Printed materials have been transferred to the book collection of The Bancroft Library.
17 volumes were initially deposited with the collection. Volumes 12-16 contained materials comprising three published titles. These were transferred to the book collection:
Suffragist; official weekly organ of the National Woman's Party (fJK1880.S8)
The Suffragette; official organ of the Woman's Social and Political Union (ffJN976.S8)
Votes for women (ffJN976.V7)
Additional selected printed materials transferred to the book collection:
List of registered voters of Austin township... (fF848.A8A18)
Churchill county telephone and telegraph company. (F847.C5A18)
Elko county telephone and telegraph company.(F847.E5A18)
Elks, Benevolent and protective order of Reno lodge no. 157. (F848.R3E6)
Tax roll of Esmeralda County for the year... (F847.E8E7)
Goldconda telephone and power company.(F847.H9A18)
...List of registered voters... (F848.G6A18)
The winning of Nevada for woman suffrage, including oration of Hon. Curtis J. Hillyer, delivered before a joint session of the Nevada Legislature in 1869. An unanswerable argument for the suffrage cause...(F846.H5)
...Mormonism, the Islam of America, by Bruce Kinney..(F835.K7)
Program...22nd year. Leisure hour club, Carson City, Nev. (F848.C2L4)
...An act to provide for the organization and government of irrigation districts...(F845.25.N4 1919)
Nevada. Laws, statutes, etc. (F846.4.N4 1918)
Journals... Nevada. Legislature (F846.1.N4 1864/5)
...Official returns of the election... Nov. 1918.(F846.4.N5)
Nevada. University...Alumni bulletin...[no.1] (F844.E3N5)
Nevada consolidated telephone and telegraph company. Telephone directory [of Carson City]... (F848.C2A18)
Nevada federation of women's clubs. Year book, 1913/14.(F837.N35)
Nevada state equal suffrage association. Proceedings of the...annual convention. (F837.N5x)
Telephone directory...Tonopah, Goldfield, Manhattan, Hornsilver, Rhyolite, Beatty, Pioneer, Springdale... (F848.T6A18)
List of registered voters... Nov. 7, 1917.(fF848.R3A18)
How we won the vote in California, a true story of the campaign of 1911... (F863.S8)
List of registered voters... Nov. 7, 1916. (fF848.S6A18)
Nevada land grants. Hearings before the Committee on the public lands, House of representatives...(F845.1.U5)
...List of registered voters... Nov. 7, 1916.(fF848.V4A18)
Acquisition Information
The Anne Henrietta Martin Papers were deposited in The Bancroft Library by Anne Martin in October 1939. Additions were made on April 18, 1940. On January 21, 1941 the collection became the property of The Bancroft Library as a permanent gift courtesy of Anne Martin through the cooperation of her neice, Edna Martin Parratt. One last set of additions was a gift of Edna Martin Parratt after Anne Martin's death in 1951.
Biography
Anne Henrietta Martin was born in Empire City, Nevada, Sept. 30, 1875, the daughter of William O'Hara Martin and Louise Stadtmuller Martin. She received her A.B. from the University of Nevada in 1894 and also an A.B. and M.A. in history from Stanford University in 1896 and 1897. From 1899-1901, she studied at Columbia University and the Universities of Leipzig and London. She headed the History Department of the University of Nevada from 1897-1899, and again resumed this post in 1901, at which time she also lectured in art history. From 1906 until 1910, she was active in the British suffrage campaign and while in London, Anne Martin met the Herbert Hoovers through her friend, Mary Austin. Also, while in London, Anne Martin was imprisoned for suffrage demonstrations. From 1911 to 1914, she was president of the Nevada Equal Franchise Society and organized the women of Nevada. In 1914, due to her efforts, suffrage was won for Nevada women. She was appointed to the Nevada Educational Survey Commission in 1915 while from 1915 to 1918, she was active in the National Women's Party, where she served as National Chairman, and the National American Women's Suffrage Association.
In 1918, she campaigned for the Senate as an Independent to fill the post vacated by the death of Senator Newlands -the first woman to run for a senatorial office in the United States. Out of 20,000 votes cast, Anne Martin polled 5,000. She again ran for this office in 1920 as an Independent and again was defeated.
In 1926, Anne Martin became Western regional director for the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom. She was a delegate to the World's Congress in Dublin in 1926 and again in Prague in 1929. Jane Addams was also very active in this group. In 1936, Anne Martin resigned from the organization due to a personal disagreement with the executive secretary. She then became involved with the People's Mandate to Governments to End War.
From 1940 until her death in 1951, Anne Martin wrote various magazine articles, including a biographical sketch of Josephine Butler that appeared in the 1944 edition of the Encyclopaedia Britannica, and later, an article on White Slavery that appeared in the 1948 edition of the Britannica. She made her home in Reno, Nevada, and Carmel, California, and died in Carmel, April 1951.
Scope and Content
Papers pertaining to Martin's activities for woman suffrage, feminism, social hygiene, and pacificism. Also included are materials relating to her U.S. Senate campaigns in Nevada in 1918 and 1920. Correspondents include: Dean Acheson, Jane Addams, Gertrude Atherton, Mary Austin, Mary Ritter Beard, Carrie Chapman Catt, Katherine Fisher, Henry Ford, Charlotte Perkins Gilman, Herbert Hoover, Cordell Hull, Belle La Follette, Henry Cabot Lodge, Margaret Long, H.L. Mencken, Francis G. Newlands, Alice Paul, Key Pittman, Jenette Rankin, Theodore Roosevelt, Upton Sinclair, Margaret Chase Smith, Lincoln Steffens, Dorothy Thompson, Mabel Vernon, Charles Erskine Scott Wood, Margaret Wood, and Maud Younger. The correspondence is supplemented by a large bulk of manuscripts and notes, pamphlets, magazine and newspaper clippings, campaign miscellany, suffrage material, personalia, and scrapbooks.
The collection has been divided into three series:
Correspondence
General Papers
Personalia
History -- 20th century -- United States. Congress. Senate.; Feminism -- History -- 20th century; Women -- Suffrage -- History.; Women Political activity; Martin, Anne, 1875-1951
- Correspondence, 1892-1951; box 1-19
  - General Correspondence, 1892-1951; Sub-Series 1; Boxes 1-12
    - Unidentified letters (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anonymous letters (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Addams, Jane, 1914-1935; Letters: 97 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Scope and Content
      2 letters, one signed by Roger Baldwin, director.
    - American Social Hygiene Association, 1948-1949; 7 letters (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anedon, Beulah, November 7-8, 1916; 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arkell, Reta S., 1916-1918; 3 letters (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Austin, Mary (Hunter), 1918, undated; 8 letters (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baker, Abby Scott, July-September 1916; 10 letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Balch, Emily Greene, 1929-1931; 11 letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Balzar, Idelle S., April-September 1918; 4 letters (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Barrett, Laura A., June-July 1920; 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baumann, Sophia E., 1913-1948; 11 letters (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1942-1951; 25 letters (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Beck, Anne A., 1914-1916; 3 letters (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Belford, Helen I., April 26, 1915, undated; 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Belford, Samuel, 1914-1915; 6 letters (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Blackwell, Sallie H., 1898-1915; 10 letters (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Blake, Katherine Devereux, 1914-1928; 19 letters (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Blatch, Harriot, Stanton, 1914-1916; 4 letters (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Boeckel, Florence Brewer, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Scope and Contents
      3 letters. Includes copy of letter to Mary Austin (May 4, 1918)
    - Bonnifield, Helen, 1914-1916; 31 letters (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Boston Equal Suffrage Association for Good Government, February-October 1915; 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Boswell, Bessie, 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bowen, Louise de Koven, 1935-1949; 18 letters (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Boyle, Emmet D., 1915-1922; 11 letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bradley, May, September 22- October 6, 1914; 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Brady, Margaret, September 30-October 22, 1916; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bragg, Jeanette E., May-August 1912; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brannan, V.D., March 4-12, 1918; 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bray, Bear, 2 cards (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bray, John Edwards, 1913-1915; 4 letters (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bray, Mary B., March 11-23, 1914; 4 letters (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bray, Minnie L., 1911-1915 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      44 letters; written as President of Carson City Nevada, Equal Franchise Society
    - Bray, Nita, 1913-1914; 7 letters (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - British Social Hygiene Council, March-May 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      2 letters; signed by Eleanor French, Council Secretary
    - Brown, Marjorie, 1913-1916; 13 letters (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bulkley, Mary, September-October 1914; 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Burlingame, Emma, 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Burton, C.F., November 13-16-1916; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bushnell, Katharine C., 1943-1944; 15 letters (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Caine, Mae, 1912-1914; 13 letters (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - California, University of, 1939-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      20 letters. Some from Herbert I. Priestly, as Director of Bancroft Library and Robert Underhill, Secretary of the Regents
    - Columbia University Press, April-May 1949; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Comins, H.A., October-November 1916; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Condon, Mallie, 1912-1929; 5 letters (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage, 1915-1916; 21 letters (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Connely, Mrs. C.L., 1915-1918; 7 letters (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Consolidated Press Clipping Company, 1916-1918; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cotterill, Grace Benefiel, 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Crane-Gartz, Kate, 1942-1945; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Crans, Lillian, August-October 1916; 5 letters (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Crisler, Clara M., October 1916; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Cumberson, Katherine D., 1927-1928; 12 letters (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Current History Magazine, July, November 1926 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      2 letters. One signed by Spencer Brodney, the other by George W. Ochs Oakes
    - Cushing, Elizabeth, 1912-1916; 7 letters (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Daugherty, Harry L., November 1920; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Davis, Mabel, September-November 1916; 5 letters (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Democratic National Committee, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      2 letters. Signed by Katherine Bass.
    - Denver, University of, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      2 letters. One signed by Ben M. Cherrington.
    - Deummond, Mrs. F., October 1916; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - C (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Driesch, Magarete, 1926-1929; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Drury, Wells, March 1919; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - E (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Campbell, Agnes, October 1916; 9 letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Eather, Effie, 1913-1914; 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Cannon, Laura Gregg, 1913-1915; 59 letters (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Eichelberger, Bessie, 1914-1942; 38 letters (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Card, Anne, 1912-1913; 14 letters (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1914-1950; 27 letters. Some signed by Walter Yust concerning articles written by Martin. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Carmel Development Company, 1916-1920; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Equal Franchise Society of Philadelphia, May-September 1914; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Case, Frances, 1915-1916; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Esmeralda County, 1913-1914; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Catlin, Mrs. W. Prince, 1912-1913; 4 letters (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Espeset, Marie, February-March 1915; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1914-1940; 5 letters (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chapin, N.H., April-September 1913; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Federation Abolitioniste & Internationale, April-May 1949; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Chicago, University of, 1943-1948; 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Feickert, Lillian F., April 1915; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Chicago Tribune, September-October 1916; 4 letters (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Field, Sara Bard, 1914-1919; 14 letters (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Church, Florence, 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Fisher, Katharine, 1916-1919; 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Clark, Jessie Leonard, 1911-1916; 31 letters (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Fitzgerald, Mae B., 1912-1913; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Close, Daisy S., September 1914; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Flannigan, Minnie, 1914-1918; 21 letters (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Cohn, Felicia, 1912-1913; 9 letters (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Foley, Margaret, 1914-1915; 11 letters (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Coleman, Ben W., 1913-1918; 3 letters (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Fountain, Sue, 1916; 6 letters (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Collins, Mrs. W.E., October 1914; 2 letters (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Fowler, Eleanor, August 1936; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Freudenberger, 1912-1913; 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Frey, Mrs. Walter, 1914-1915; 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Fulton, Christye, 1912-1914; 9 letters (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Funk, Antoinette, 1914-1915; 10 letters (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - G (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gann, Birdie, 1914-1915; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Garfinkle, Julius and Company, 1918-1920; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - George, Julia, 1915-1916; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Gill, E.M., January-February 1914; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Gilman, Charlotte Perkins, 1915-1919; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Givens, Esther K., 1912-1913; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Good Housekeeping, 1918-1922 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      11 letters. Signed by Clara Savage and M.F. Bigelow, as editors. Concerning articles by Anne Martin.
    - Grant, Sara, October-November 1916; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Granville-Smith, Jessica, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Gregory, Gertrude, 1916-1949; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Gulling, Amy J., September-October 1913; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Gurney, Jane, February-March 1913; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - H (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hamerstrom, Helen H.D., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Hamilton, Alice, 1934-1935; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hamilton, S.H., September 1920; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Harder, Emily, 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Harding, Ida, October 1-4, 1914; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Harper, Ida Husted, 1919-1929; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hascall, Nellie B., May-October 1913; 10 letters (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Hatch, S.F., October 18-28, 1916; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Havemeyer, William Frederick, 1918-1919; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Hawaii- Department of Health, June-August 1949; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Hearst's International, July-August 1922 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      2 letters. Signed by Norman Hapgood as editor.
    - Heffernan, Helen, October-November 1916; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Helm, Annie, September-October 1914; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Henkle, Alice, 1916-1919; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Henry, M.A., July-August 1916; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Heskett, John, March-April 1918; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Hill, Elsie, September-November 1916; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Hilles, Florence Bayard, October 24-31, 1919; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hoegh, Laura, 1912-1913; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1916-1941 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      4 letters. One signed by Lawrence Richey.
    - Hoover, Lou Henry, 1914-1918; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Hopkins, Alison H., October-November 1916; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Hopkins, J.A.H., February-April 1919; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Hopper, Joseph C., June-July 1915; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Horton, J.B., October 4-15, 1914; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Houghton, Lewis, November 4-17, 1916; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Howard, Elbert, 1916-1918; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Hull, Hannah Clothier, 1926-1935; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Hull House, 1914-1938; 9 letters (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Hummel, Nora Quinlan, April-June 1915; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Hunt, Mae G., February-March 1915; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Hurlbut, Julia, September-November 1916; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - I (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Illinois Equal Suffrage Association, 1914-1915; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Independent Corporation, 1920; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - International Free Trade League, May-November 1918; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Iowa Equal Suffrage Association, 1914-1915; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - J (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Jackson, Austin, June-October 1914; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Jenkins, Edith, 1912-1913; 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Jenkins, Mabel, 1913-1916; 10 letters (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Jensen, George, October 6-10, 1914; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Johnson, Lucy B., 1914-1915; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Just Government League of Maryland, 1914-1919; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - K (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Kaeding, Mrs. George Ladd, 1915-1916; 6 letters (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Kampmann, Niels, 1926-1927; 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Kaneko, J., September-October 1914; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Keeler, Mrs. P.E., 1912-1913; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Kemble, Mrs. Tiny G., 1914-1915; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Kennaday, Paul, 1922-1925; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Kenny, Annie, October 18-23, 1914; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Kent, Elizabeth, 1914-1919; 17 letters (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Kent, William, 1914-1919; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Kerlin, Tenney G., November 15-23, 1915; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - L (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Landsberg, Clara, September-October 1929; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Lawson, Mrs. W.J., May-July 1912; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - League of Nations Association, 1929-1939; 5 letters (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Leech, Gertrude, 1943; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Levrs, Anita, 1922; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Lewis, Austin, January 18, 1939; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Library of Congress, 1948-1949; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Lipman, Mrs. J.A., November 2-5, 1916; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, January-February 1919; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Long, Margaret, 1916-1948; 14 letters (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Lovelock Publishing Company, October 12-27, 1914; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Luce, Inez, September 24-27, 1914; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Lyceum Club, 1920-1929; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lyman, Robert W., October 10-22, 1914; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - M (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - McCarran, Patrick A., 1916-1946; 5 letters (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - McCormick, Medill, October 16-24, 1914; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - McCreery, Maud Leonard, 1914-1918; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - McCulloch, Catherine W., February 4-15, 1915; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - McDonald, Minnie M., 1914-1915; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Mackrelle, Ida, October 30-November 4, 1916; 6 letters (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - McMann, Hortense, September 28-29, 1916; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Mahon, Grace, 6 letters (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Marston, Helen D., 1928-1930; 7 letters (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Martin, John, September-October 1918; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Martin, Louise W., 1910-1914; 6 letters (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Mason Valley News, 1914-1915; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association, 1914-1916; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Milholland, Vida, 1929-1951; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Miller, A. Grant, April 20-22-1915; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Miller, Mrs. Anna L., 1912-1913; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Miller, Clarence B., February-May 1919; 14 letters (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Miller, J.A., April-August 1912; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Mills, Ethelwyn, 1928-1930; 18 letters (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Minnesota Woman's Suffrage Association, 1914-1916; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Mississippi Valley Suffrage Association, February-March 1916; 5 letters (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Missouri Equal Suffrage Association, September-October 1914; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Moore, Sybil Jane, 1929-1930; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Morley, Ada, 1914; 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Mouffe, Bessie, 1914-1915; 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Mullen, Katharine, March-April 1918; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Munds, Frances W., 1914-1915; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Mundy, Julia, 1914-1915; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Murray, Mabel G., March-October 1913; 7 letters (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Murrish, Harry J., October-November 1916; 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - N (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Nation, 1921-1940; 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - National American Woman's Suffrage Association, 1915-1916; 26 letters (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - National Arts Club, 1929-1938; 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - National Consumers' League, 1915-1920; 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - National Council of Women Voters, 1914-1915; 8 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - National Party, March-May 1918; 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - National Progressive Committee (Box 6, Folder 8)